## **ALEXANDRA BARKA**

# Front End Engineer

barka.alexandra2@gmail.com - ale3oula.github.io - +306949413084

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a **Front End Engineer** with experience in building software and web applications. I enjoy creating **simple** and **creative** user interfaces using modern web technologies. I'm excited about learning new skills as well as improving my current. Currently, I am focusing on expanding my skills in Angular 7 and learning Vue.js.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **UBITECH Ltd.**, UX Engineer

July 2018 - Today

Working in several projects using several web technologies (Angular 7, Vue.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular JS, Thymeleaf). My responsibilities include creating front end components and services by using the best practices and integrating with a REST API.

ICS FORTH, Research & Development assistant - UI/UX Engineer

Jul 2015 - Jun 2018

Worked as a research assistant in the HCI Laboratory of FORTH. Researcher and developer in Ambient Intelligent environments. Outcomes from my work in FORTH are:

- **Ulnify**. A full stack application (MEAN stack) which acted as a studio for composing flexible web applications in real-time and aggregate all the individual UIs of an intelligent environment by introducing new rich user interface compositions.
- Beantable. Co-develop an augmented interactive table with multiple games for the Heraklion Public Library of Crete. Used C# and WPF to implement a launcher for the application and re-design various games (e.g. puzzle, classic memory games).
- Arkadi Monastery. Re-design and develop a mobile application for the Arkadi Museum in Rethimni.
  Used Actionscript and Adobe Flash Builder to implement a cross-platform application for both Android and iOS.
- Info kiosk. Co-developed an info kiosk for the Archeological Museum of Crete, which provided information for the Minoan Culture. Developed in C# and WPF the Architecture section and some Utilities.

#### **EDUCATION**

## M.Sc. in Information Systems and HCI

2016-2018

University of Crete Grade: 9.28

 Coursework included Introduction and advanced topics on HCI, Information Retrieval, DBMS, BPMS and Knowledge Representation and Reasoning. Teaching Assistant in Introduction on HCI (Spring 2018), Modern Topics on HCI (Winter 2017) and Data Structures (2016-2017).

**Thesis Topic**: Ulnify: A Designer Studio for creating UI Mashups for Ambient Intelligence Environments, *presented November 2018, Heraklion, Crete* 

## **B.Sc.** in Computer Science

2011-2016

University of Crete Grade: 8.19

 Coursework included HCI, Web programming, Data Structures, Compilers, Algorithms and Complexity and more. Volunteered as a TA in Computer Organisation and Introduction to C programming coursed.

**Thesis Topic:** Requirements analysis and development of conceptual model of an information system for food traceability.